## Robert B. Corlett

1 Sunshine Ct. • Newport, RI 02840 (541) 914-4038 • corlett.robert@gmail.com

#### PROFILE

I'm an iOS engineer with a leadership habit. I love solving problems and leading by example. I'm looking for a position where I can positively impact others while learning from teammates with experiences different than my own. I bring with me over 5 years of professional iOS development experience writing enterprise level software for a platform that publishes thousands of apps to the app store monthly, servicing millions of user (crowdcompass.com).

### CURRENT

Languages: Swift, Objective-C

**ENVIRONMENT IDE:** Xcode

SCM: Git, Stash CI: Jenkins

Testing: XCTest, OCMock, OHTTPStubs, Postman, Test Flight, Calabash

**Dependency Management:** Cocoapods **Project Management:** Jira, Trello, Slack

3rd Party Libs: AFNetworking/Alamofire, SQLCipher, Mixpanel,

CocoaLumberjack, PubNub, Nimbus, FMDB, NewRelic

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Principal Software Engineer,** January 2018 - July 2018

Cvent, Inc

- Worked across divisions to launch the development of a shared analytics library leveraging an internal analytics solution in order to reduce costly third party dependencies
- Created working group of managers focused on improving employee satisfaction through things like improved managerial transparency, unified managerial communication, and affecting positive organizational change based on employee feedback
- Maintained two cross-functional teams with zero employee turnover for over three years by putting first things like employee development, clarity of vision, and transparency of expectations, all while exceeding benchmarks for team productivity and release quality

## **Lead Software Engineer,** January 2015 - December 2018 Cvent. Inc

- Managed two cross-functional teams of developers while acting as the lead iOS developer for one of those teams, releasing high-visibility features every two weeks for years
- Coached, and mentored client-side software engineers across both teams to help improve their technical, interpersonal, and leadership skills
- Worked with recruiting teams to attract, hire, onboard, and retain talented engineers across all functional disciplines within our organization
- Collaborated with managers and contributors across the organization to create, communicate, and refine policies to improve quality, productivity, and the overall happiness of my coworkers

# **iOS Software Engineer,** September 2013 - January 2015 Cvent, Inc

• Responsible for extending and maintaining attendee-facing iOS

- applications used daily by thousands of event goers
- Collaborated closely with Android, server, and front end web developers to deliver high quality feature parity across a large and varied feature set

## Quality Engineer, June 2011 - September 2013

CrowdCompass, Inc (Acquired by Cvent, Inc)

- Crafted unit tests for iOS applications using Sentest and OCMock and Android applications using JUnit
- Created automated suite of Ruby scripts for testing and interacting with RESTful web API used by both QA and Development teams
- Coordinated growth of QA department, hiring and training a QA Lead, 3
  Test Associates and 2 SQEs on all aspects of product

## CURRENT SIDE PROJECTS

#### Clean Ocean Access

A Swift prototype application for local non-profit to help improve volunteer efficiency when reporting on public ocean access points.

## Heyyy

I am the 2nd developer on a social iOS application for sharing styled written messages from across the room. Written in ObjC, I am volunteering some of my time for this project to stay sharp in this language.

### 8-bit Tidal Clock

Arduino Uno project to display local tide data in an artistic way. It fetches data from NOAA buoys and updates an LED array that displays an ocean scene reflective of the current tide.

#### **EDUCATION**

Post Baccalaureate Studies in Computer Engineering, 2009 - 2011 Portland State University, Portland Oregon (GPA 3.98)

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, Received Sept. 2007 Concentration in Entrepreneurship University of Oregon, Eugene, Oregon (GPA 3.62)

### **REFERENCES** A

Available upon request